Franz Boas Professional Papers ca.1860-1942 Mss.B.B61p
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Professional Papers, ca.1860-1942; Collection II; 12.5 linear feet
  - Boas, Franz (Box 2-17)
    - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1850s-1942, n.d. (Box 3-12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1892 Jan. - March (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1892 Apr. - May (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1892 June - Aug. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1892 Oct. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1892 Nov. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1892 Dec. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1893 Jan. - March (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1893 April - July (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1893 Aug. - Oct. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1893 Nov. - Dec. (Box 6)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1894 Jan. - Feb. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1894 March - May (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1894 June - Aug. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1894 Sept. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1894 Oct. 1 - 21 (Box 7)
        12 October 1894--sketches
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1894 Oct. 21 - 31 (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1894 Nov. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1894 Dec. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1895 Jan. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1895 Feb. - March (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1895 Apr. - June (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1895 July - Aug. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1895 Oct. - Dec. (Box 7)
        19 November 1895--sketches
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1896 Jan. - March (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1896 April - June (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1896 July (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1896 Aug. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1896 Sept. - Oct. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1896 Nov. - Dec. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1897 Jan. - Mar. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1897 April - May (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1897 June (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1897 July (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1897 Aug. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1897 Sept. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1897 Oct. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1897 Nov. - Dec. (Box 7)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1898 Jan. - March (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1898 April - July (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1898 Aug. - Sept. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1898 Oct. - Dec. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1899 Jan. - Feb. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1899 Mar. - April (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1899 May - June (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1899 July (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1899 Aug. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1899 Sept. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1899 Oct. - Dec. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1900 Jan. - Feb. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1900 March - April (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1900 May - June (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1900 July (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1900 Aug. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1900 Sept. - Oct. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1900 Nov. - Dec. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1901 Jan. - Feb. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1901 Mar. - April (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1901 May - Sept. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1901 Oct. - Dec. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1902 Jan. - March (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1902 April - May (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1902 June (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1902 July (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1902 Aug. - Sept. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1902 Oct. - Dec. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1903 Feb. - March (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1903 April - May (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1903 June - July (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1903 Aug. - Sept. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1903 Oct. - Dec. (Box 8)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1904 Jan. - March (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1904 April - Aug. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1904 Sept. - Dec. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1905 Jan. - April (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1905 May - June (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1905 July - Aug. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1905 Sept. - Oct. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1905 Nov. - Dec. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1906 Jan. - March (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1906 April - June (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1906 July - Aug. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1906 Sept. - Oct. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1906 Nov. - Dec. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1907 Jan. - Mar. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1907 April - May (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1907 June (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1907 July (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1907 Aug. - Sept. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1907 Oct. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1907 Nov. - Dec. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1908 Jan. - Feb. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1908 March - May (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1908 June - Aug. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1908 Sept. - Oct. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1908 Nov. - Dec. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1909 Jan. - Feb. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1909 March - April (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1909 May - June (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1909 July - Aug. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1909 Sept. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1909 Oct. - Dec. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1910 Jan. - March (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1910 April - June (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1910 July - Aug. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1910 Sept. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1910 Oct. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1910 Nov. - Dec. (Box 9)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1911 Jan. - Feb. (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1911 March (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1911 April - June (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1911 July - Sept. (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1911 Oct. (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1911 Nov.; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1911 Dec.; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1912 Jan.; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1912 Feb.; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1912 March; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1912 April (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1912 May - Aug. (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1913 Jan. - April; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1913 May - July; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1913 Aug. - Oct. (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1913 Nov. - Dec. (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1914. Jan. - May (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1914 June; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1914 July; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1914 Aug. (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1914 Sept. (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1914 Oct. - Dec. (Box 10)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1915 Jan. - April (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1915 May (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1915 June (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1915 July; 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1915 Aug. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1915 Sept. - Dec. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1916 Jan. - April (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1916 May - Sept. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1916 Nov. - Dec. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1917 Jan. - May (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1917 June - July (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1917 Aug. - Dec. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1918 Jan. - May (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1918 June (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1918 July (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1918 Aug. - Sept. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1918 Oct. - Dec. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1919 Jan. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1919 Feb. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1919 March - April (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1919 May (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1919 June (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1919 July - Aug. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1919 Sept. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1919 Oct. - Nov. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1919 Dec. (Box 11)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1920 Jan. - March (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1920 April - May (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1920 June (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1920 July (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1920 Aug. - Sept. (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1920 Oct. - Dec. (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1921 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1921 Jan. - April (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1921 May - July (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1921 Aug. - Dec. (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1922 Jan. - May (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1922 June (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1922 July - Dec. (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1923 Jan. - April (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1923 May - Aug. (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1923 Sept. - Oct. (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1923 Nov. - Dec. (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1924 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1925 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1927 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1928 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1929 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1930; 3 folders (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1931; 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1932; 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1933 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1934 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1935 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1936 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1937 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1938 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1941 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence, 1942 (Box 12)
      - Boas, Franz -- Correspondence (Box 12)
    - Boas, Franz -- Curriculum Vitae, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Boas, Franz -- Diary (Box 13-14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary, 1886; Carbon copy, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary (2nd copy), 1886; Carobn copy, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary [Translation], 1886; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary [Typed translation], 1886; 3 folders (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary [Typed translation], 1886; 4 folders (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary, 1888 (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary, 1888; Carbon copy (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary [Translation], 1888 (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary [Translation], 1888 (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary [Typed transcription], 1888 (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary, 1889; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary, 1889; Carbon copy, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary, 1890 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary [Translation], 1890 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Diary, ca.1911 - 1912 (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- Eine Harsreise, 1881 (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- Evening Post, Feb., 1917 (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- Field notes, British Colombia [Translation], 1889 (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- House in Grantwood, N. J., Building Contract, 1907 (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- "Indianische Sagen" (Review of) (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- Kwakuitl (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- Kwakiutl dictionary [See notebooks at the end of the collection], 1922 (Box 22)
    - Boas, Franz -- Kwakiutl ethnographic texts, 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- Kwakiutl field notebooks, c. 1930 - 1931 (Box 14, 22)
    - Boas, Franz -- Kwakiutl semantics (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- Kwakiutl vocabulary, stems, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- Leases (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- Lectures (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - "The Art of the North American Indian", 1897 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - Clark University, 1898 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - Commencement Address at Atlanta University, (May 31, 1906) (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - "Growth", 1898 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - "The `ice-relationship' of the Arctic Ocean", 1885 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - Inaugural lecture before the students, 1885 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - Jessup Expedition, 1898 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - "Primitive Art", 1896 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - "Primitive Languages", 1896 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - "Primitive Religion", 1896 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - "Primitive Society", 1896 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - "The Races of Man", 1896 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures, 1895 March 2 (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures VIII - XIII, 1912 [1917] (Box 14)
        Boas - Lectures - 1912 - VIII - XIII
        Should be 1917 - VIII - XIII
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - I - VI, 1916 - (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - VII - X, 1916 - (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - I - VII, 1917 - (Box 14)
      - Boas, Franz -- Lectures - XIV - XX, 1917 - (Box 14)
    - Boas, Franz -- Library (Box 15)
    - Boas, Franz -- Library catalogue, 8 folders (Box 15)
    - Boas, Franz -- New York Times (Box 15)
    - Boas, Franz -- "Notes of museum work, May 25 - Dec., 1905" (Box 15)
    - Boas, Franz -- Notebook, n.d. (Box 15)
    - Boas, Franz -- Paper (Box 15-16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - Address to Barnard Class in Anthropology, Nov., 1912 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - Address at dinner for F. W. Putnam (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [American Democracy] (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The American Ethnological Society", 1942 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Analysis of the Growth Curve of Man", 1930 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "An anthropologist's view of war", n.d. (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Anthropology in University and College", 1907 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Created Equal", 1942 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Democracy and Intellectual Freedom", Aug. 21, 1939 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Democracy and Intellectual Freedom", 1939 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Die Klassifikation der Indianischen Sprachen", 1925 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Die Offentliche Meinung in Vereinigtnen Staaten und der europaische Kieg", ca. 1914 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Education, Freedom & Democracy], 1940 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Education & Intellectual Freedom], 1940 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The Eskimos of Baffin Land", 1885 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Evolution and Environment], 1909 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Freedom Defined", 1941 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Freedom of Education], 1941 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Freedom of Science], 1938 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The Freedom of Science", 1939 (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Freedom of Thought", [1941] (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Germany] (Box 15)
      - [Boas, Franz] - Paper - [Gestures] (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Growth] (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Growth", n.d. (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The Great Melting Pot and Its Problems", 1921 (Box 15)
      - [Boas, Franz] - Paper - [Haida Linguistics] (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - Handbook of American Indian Languages (preface) (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Heredity] (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Heredity and Environment" (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [High Schools in Bergen Co., N. J.] (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Immigrants and Immigration] (Box 15)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The Indians of British Colombia," (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Individual, Family, Population and Race", 1942 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Influence of Environment", n.d. (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Intellectual Freedom in Nazi Germany", 1938 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Interdependence of Culture" (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The International State and the League of Nations" (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Interpretation of Indian Myths" (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - Interracial Unity Meeting, Carnegie Hall, April 14, 1939 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - Introduction to David Effron article, n.d. (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Japanese Americans], Dec. 30, 1941 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The Jew and the World", 1936 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Letters of a Non-Partisan", 1915 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - Letters of a Non-Partisan, 1917 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The Mental Attitude of the Educated Classes", 1918 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "My Reasons against America's Participation in the War", April 30, 1917 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The Myth of the Race", 1941 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Nationalism" (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Nationalism, Internationalism, Individualism" (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - Pan-American Democracy, 1941 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Polar Exploration, Peary and Cook", 1909 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The policy of Endowed Colleges & Universities of the War Period" (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Political Opinion Among the German Intellectuals", n.d. (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Population and Racism (?)" (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The Primitive Mind and the Present Hour, c. 1917? (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Public Schools], April 13, 1940 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Public Schools], March 12, 1941 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - Publications of the Jessup North Pacific Expedition (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Race], 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Race and Culture" (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Racism & Fascism in Italy] (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Recent Anthropology", 1942 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Reflections on the War", 1915; 5 folders (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The Relation between Physical & Mental Development", 1941 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Report by Franz Boas on the study of the Relative Influence of Heredity and Environment" (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Report on work on Heredity and Environment" (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - Response to Johannes Stark's article in Nature, 1938 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Science and Patriotism", 1915 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Science and Race Mythology", 1939 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Science in Nazi Germany", 1937 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Scientists as Spies", 1919 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [Sterilization] (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Ten Statements about Race", n.d. (Box 16)
      - [Boas, Franz] - Paper - "Tentative Plan for Educational Work in Mexico", n.d. (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "Testimony of Science", 1915 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "This Nordic Nonsense", 1925 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "The Tribes of the North Pacific Coast", 1905 (Box 16)
      - [Boas, Franz] - Paper - "Under the Arctic Circle" (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - "What is a Nation", 1919 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - [World War II], 1940 (Box 16)
      - Boas, Franz -- Paper - Unidentified, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Boas, Franz -- Radio address, Feb. 11, 1939 (Box 17)
    - Boas, Franz -- Radio address, 1941 September (Box 17)
    - Boas, Franz -- Radio address, n.d. (Box 17)
    - Boas, Franz -- Recommendations for Johns Hopkins Fellowship, 1882 (Box 17)
    - Boas, Franz -- Reminiscences of his life (Box 17)
    - Boas, Franz -- Reviews of books (Box 17)
    - Boas, Franz -- Speech - Anti-Nazi Meeting, [1936] (Box 17)
    - Boas, Franz -- Speech before National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, 1941 March 12 (Box 17)
    - Boas, Franz -- Suggested Lectures on Linguistics (Box 17)
    - Boas, Franz -- Visa (Box 17)
  - Boas, Ernst, 25 folders (Box 17)
    - Boas, Ernst, 22 folders (Box 17)
    - Letters to parents [Transcripts], 1907-1918 (Box 17)
    - Notes on a conversation with Franz Boas, 1940 or 1941 (Box 17)
    - Reminiscenses of his Father (Box 17)
  - Boas Family - Genealogical and ancestral data, 6 folders (Box 18)
  - Boas Family - Genealogy (Box 18)
  - Boas Family - Mortgages (Box 18)
  - Boas, Franz and Marie - Wedding congratulations, 1887 (Box 18)
  - Boas, Franz and Marie - Letters to Ernst, 1918 - 1922 (Box 18)
  - Boas, Marie (Box 18)
  - Boas, Marie Krackowizer (Box 18)
  - [Boas], Marie Krackowizer - Diary, 1880 (Box 18)
  - Boas, Sophie to Franz & Marie Boas [Transcript translations], 1892 - 1896 (Box 18)
  - Boas, Sophie & Meier - Wills (Box 18)
  - Bogoras, Vladimir (Box 18)
  - Bogoras, Waldemar G. (Box 18)
  - Bohme, Traugott (Box 18)
  - Bowditch, Dr. H. P. (Box 18)
  - Breton, Mrs. (Box 18)
  - Bunzel, Ruth (Box 18)
  - Bureau of Ethnology - Budget (Box 18)
  - Burr, [Geo. Lincoln]? - "Insanity" (Box 18)
  - Butler, Nicholas M. (Box 18)
  - Cattell, James McKeen, 5 folders (Box 18)
    - Cattell, James McKeen (Box 18)
    - Confidential Memo, re: Cattell vs. Columbia University, 1920 (Box 18)
    - Memo Concerning our Scientific Departments (Columbia University), 1910 (Box 18)
    - "University Control", 1906 (Box 18)
    - "What the Trustees of Columbia University Have Done", 1918 (Box 18)
  - Cattell, Owen - et al (Box 18)
  - Chamberlain, Alexander F. (Box 18)